Hello everyone and welcome back to another edition here at EnglishPod.
大家好，欢迎回到EnglishPod的另一期节目。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And my name is Catherine and today we've got a great upper intermediate level lesson for
我是Catherine，今天我们为大家准备了一节很棒的中高级课程，主题是
you all about animal and human rights.
动物权利和人类权利。
Right.
没错。
So it's a very debatable topic.
这是一个非常有争议的话题。
People want to protect animals, mistreatment of animals.
人们想要保护动物，反对虐待动物。
And this is what we're going to talk about today, protecting animals and giving them
这就是我们今天要讨论的内容——保护动物并赋予它们
rights.
权利。
Do you think animals have rights?
你觉得动物有权利吗？
Eh, well, you know, I think we could leave that for the end.
嗯，这个嘛，我觉得我们可以把这个问题留到最后讨论。
I don't want to, you know, influence the argument here in today's dialogue.
我不想影响今天对话中的论点。
But yeah, as you've said, I think it's very much a topic that people can go both ways
但就像你说的，我认为这个话题确实让人们可以
on.
持不同观点。
So why don't we listen to our dialogue as two people discuss animal rights and let's
那我们不如来听听对话，看看两个人如何讨论动物权利，
get their opinions on things.
听听他们的看法。
You should have seen the TV show that was on last night.
你真该看看昨晚的电视节目。
The topic it covered was really interesting.
它讨论的话题非常有趣。
Animal rights.
动物权利。
Do you really believe in that?
你真的相信这个吗？
If they're going to focus on something, they should do it on civil rights.
如果他们要把精力放在某件事上，应该放在民权上。
Yes, but we can't deny that animals are vulnerable, defenseless and are completely at the mercy
是的，但我们不能否认动物是脆弱的、无助的，完全受
of human beings.
人类支配。
I understand your point, but we continue to have transgressions against human rights.
我理解你的观点，但人类权利仍然不断受到侵犯。
If so much attention weren't devoted to the topic of animals, we would then concentrate
如果对动物话题的关注不那么集中，我们就能更专注于
more on saving a human being instead of protecting a koala.
拯救人类，而不是保护一只考拉。
You can't compare apples and oranges.
你不能把苹果和橘子相提并论。
I believe that both topics are important and that we can't ignore them.
我认为这两个话题都很重要，我们不能忽视它们。
The mistreatment of animals can cause a great environmental imbalance.
虐待动物会导致严重的生态失衡。
I believe that governments should prohibit activities like poaching.
我认为政府应该禁止偷猎等活动。
Well, you are right on that point.
嗯，在这一点上你说得对。
This is the reason that I don't buy leather and I try to buy synthetic products.
这就是我不买皮革，尽量买合成产品的原因。
At least you're doing your part.
至少你在尽自己的一份力。
My contribution is to have a pet in the house that I treat like a member of the family.
我的贡献是养了一只宠物，把它当作家人一样对待。
As long as you don't treat it better than your wife, it's fine.
只要你别对它比对你老婆还好，那就没问题。
All right, we're back and both of them have good points, right?
好了，我们回来了，他们两个都有道理，对吧？
In favor and against.
支持和反对的都有。
As you said, they also talk about human rights, which is also a very important topic.
就像你说的，他们也谈到了人权，这也是一个非常重要的话题。
But before we discuss this topic, why don't we take a look at the language that was used
但在我们讨论这个话题之前，不如先来看看
now in Language Takeaway.
语言要点部分用到的语言。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, so in Language Takeaway, our first word today is vulnerable.
好的，在语言要点中，我们今天的第一个词是“vulnerable”。
Okay, vulnerable is a great word.
好，“vulnerable”是个很棒的词。
It's a way to describe something.
它是用来描述某事物的形容词。
And so something is vulnerable if it can't really protect itself.
某物如果无法真正保护自己，就是“vulnerable”的。
So you are in danger of being hurt.
所以你处于可能受到伤害的危险中。
Exactly.
没错。
Right.
对。
So you're vulnerable.
所以你是脆弱的。
Now, this isn't only used for animals, right?
这个词不仅仅用于动物，对吧？
It can be like an army is vulnerable if they don't have strong defenses on the borders.
比如，如果一支军队在边境没有强大的防御，它也是脆弱的。
Or my emotions.
或者我的情绪。
I'm feeling vulnerable because I just had a really horrible week and I'm really depressed
我感到脆弱，因为我刚经历了一个非常糟糕的一周，非常沮丧，
and I'm emotionally vulnerable.
情绪上很脆弱。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So vulnerable.
所以是“vulnerable”。
And they also talked about transgressions against human rights.
他们还谈到了“transgressions against human rights”（对人权的侵犯）。
All right, so a transgression is a thing.
好的，“transgression”是一个名词。
It's a noun.
它是名词。
And transgression is like doing something harmful to or against someone or something.
“Transgression”指的是对某人或某物做有害的事情。
So a transgression, it's a noun.
所以“transgression”是名词。
So is it doing something in a bad way?
所以是以不好的方式做事吗？
Exactly.
没错。
It's a bad thing.
是坏事。
It's always negative.
总是负面的。
It's not positive, right?
不是正面的，对吧？
Right.
对。
And so in many prayers, for example, in the Christian faith, you say, you know, Lord,
在很多祈祷中，比如基督教信仰中，你会说：“主啊，
forgive me for my transgressions, for having kind of crossed the line from doing good things
宽恕我的过犯”，意思是跨越了从做好事
to bad things.
到做坏事的界限。
So you're doing bad things.
所以你在做坏事。
Very good.
非常好。
So that's a good way of putting it, to cross the line, to kind of go beyond where you should.
所以“跨越界限”是个很好的说法，指超出了你应该的范围。
All right, so transgressions.
好的，所以是“transgressions”。
And now another very serious problem in the world is poaching.
现在世界上另一个非常严重的问题是“poaching”（偷猎）。
That's one of the things that they said they should control, poaching.
这是他们提到应该控制的事情之一，偷猎。
You might have heard this word in a different context because it does have another meaning,
你可能在其他语境中听过这个词，因为它确实有另一个意思，
but I'm just going to explain the one meaning here that we're talking about, which is killing
但我只解释我们这里讨论的这个意思，即杀害
animals, especially for sport or for selling their skins and their furs.
动物，尤其是为了娱乐或出售它们的皮毛。
Right.
对。
So that's poaching.
所以那就是偷猎。
What's the difference between poaching and hunting?
偷猎和打猎有什么区别？
Hunting can be legal.
打猎可以是合法的。
Poaching is illegal.
偷猎是非法的。
Okay.
好的。
So that's the main difference.
所以这是主要区别。
Hunting is usually for sport.
打猎通常是为了娱乐。
You hunt either for food or for sport, right?
你打猎要么是为了食物，要么是为了娱乐，对吧？
Legal hunting.
合法打猎。
But poaching is usually you want to sell, like you said, the fur or the skins or something.
但偷猎通常是为了出售，就像你说的，皮毛或兽皮之类的东西。
Or the tusks on rhinos or something like that.
或者犀牛的角之类的。
Exactly.
没错。
All right, so poaching.
好的，所以是“poaching”。
And then they talked about synthetic products.
然后他们谈到了“synthetic products”（合成产品）。
So what is a synthetic product?
那么什么是合成产品？
Well, synthetic product is something that is man-made.
嗯，合成产品是人造的东西。
So it's not natural in that it doesn't come from the earth.
所以它不是天然的，不是来自地球的。
Cotton is a natural product and plastic, for example, is synthetic or another example.
棉花是天然产品，而塑料是合成产品，或者另一个例子。
Or nylon.
或者尼龙。
Nylon is a really good synthetic product.
尼龙是一种非常好的合成产品。
And so people who don't want to use animal products like wool or leather, they prefer
所以不想使用动物产品（如羊毛或皮革）的人，更喜欢
to use synthetic products.
使用合成产品。
And I think maybe you've heard this in clothing.
我想你可能在服装中听过这个词。
It's called synthetic fibers, right?
它被称为合成纤维，对吧？
Like nylon or polyester.
比如尼龙或聚酯纤维。
Exactly.
没错。
These are all the words that we have for language takeaway today.
这些就是我们今天语言要点中的所有词汇。
So why don't we move on now to a couple of very interesting phrases that we saw in the
那我们接下来看看对话中出现的几个非常有趣的短语，
dialogue now in Fluency Builder.
在流利度构建部分。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
Okay, this first phrase is, well, it's a common one, but it's definitely not used in very
好的，第一个短语是，嗯，很常见，但绝对不是在
happy circumstances.
愉快的场合使用的。
We say that something or someone is at the mercy of someone else.
我们说某物或某人“at the mercy of”（受……支配）另一个人。
Okay, so animals are at the mercy of human beings.
好的，所以动物受人类支配。
What does this mean exactly?
这到底是什么意思？
Mercy?
“Mercy”？
So basically, it means that the animals, in this case, don't have control of what's going
基本上，这意味着动物在这种情况下无法控制
on.
发生的事情。
So human beings are the ones that control everything.
所以人类是掌控一切的一方。
So if I decide to kill them, then they are at my mercy, at my will, at my whim.
所以如果我决定杀死它们，它们就受我的支配，听凭我的意愿和一时兴起。
Exactly.
没错。
And so you could say, I'm at your mercy, Marco, please just like help me out with this.
所以你可以说，我全听你的了，Marco，请帮帮我吧。
It's like you're the one in control.
就好像你是掌控局面的人。
You're the one who can help the situation.
你是那个能帮忙解决问题的人。
Will you help?
你会帮忙吗？
Exactly.
没错。
I'm at the mercy of someone.
我受制于某人。
And then they were talking and debating this thing and an interesting comparison came up.
然后他们讨论这件事时，出现了一个有趣的比较。
You can't compare apples and oranges.
你不能把苹果和橘子相提并论。
All right, you're going to hear this all the time in English.
好了，你在英语中会经常听到这个说法。
It's not just a funny little phrase that the person uses.
这不仅仅是一个有趣的小短语。
It's a very common idiom.
这是一个非常常见的习语。
And so we say, it's like apples and oranges or you can't compare apples and oranges.
所以我们说，这就像苹果和橘子，或者你不能把苹果和橘子相提并论。
And this is essentially saying, these are two different things.
这基本上就是说，这是两件不同的事。
Completely different.
完全不同。
So I can't compare him and her because it's apples and oranges.
所以我不能拿他和她比较，因为这是苹果和橘子。
They're two different things, two different people.
他们是两件不同的事，两个不同的人。
Right.
对。
Because that's what in the movie, you said they were like peas and carrots.
因为在电影里，你说他们就像豌豆和胡萝卜。
They just go together well.
他们就是很搭配。
They just go together.
他们就是很合得来。
Does that make sense?
这说得通吗？
Not really.
不太说得通。
Forrest Gump was a little bit strange like that.
《阿甘正传》有点奇怪，就像那样。
But I think the meaning is that if I say that's a big apple and I say that's a small
但我觉得意思是，如果我说那是个大苹果，而我说那是个小苹果，
apple, they're all apples so I can compare them.
它们都是苹果，所以我可以比较。
But I say this is a really big orange and that's a really big apple.
但我说这是个很大的橘子，那是个很大的苹果。
Well, they're different.
嗯，它们不同。
You just can't compare them.
你就是没法比较。
All right.
好了。
And towards the end, the person said that you're doing your part.
在最后，那个人说你在尽自己的一份力。
You're doing your part.
你在尽自己的一份力。
Yeah, so this is a hard one to understand sometimes because it's not like a part in
是啊，这有时很难理解，因为它不像戏剧里的角色。
a play.
它更像是社会中的一部分。
It's more like a part in society.
你在帮助让社会、文化或文明变得更好。
You're helping make society or culture or civilization better.
所以你在做贡献。
So you're contributing.
没错。
Exactly.
So for example, what would be an example of a person doing their part towards society?
那么举个例子，一个人为社会尽自己的一份力是什么样的？
Well, for example, I don't own a car.
嗯，比如，我没有车。
I ride my bike and it's my way of doing my part to help the environment.
我骑自行车，这是我尽自己的一份力来帮助环境的方式。
Okay, very good.
好的，非常好。
So I can't, obviously, I can't buy a factory that's very green or I can't do all these
所以我不能，显然，我不能买一个非常环保的工厂，也不能做所有这些
things to change the world.
改变世界的事情。
So I'm going to do small things that those are my way of doing my part.
所以我会做小事，这些是我尽自己一份力的方式。
Okay.
好的。
So like another example would be recycling.
所以另一个例子是回收利用。
That's doing your part.
那就是尽自己的一份力。
Exactly.
没错。
Or in this case, the person bought only synthetic products, nothing made from nature.
或者在这个例子中，那个人只买合成产品，不买任何天然制品。
All right, very good.
好的，非常好。
So very interesting phrases.
所以是非常有趣的短语。
Why don't we listen to our dialogue for the last time and then we'll be right back.
我们最后再听一遍对话，然后马上回来。
You should have seen the TV show that was on last night.
你应该看看昨晚的电视节目。
The topic it covered was really interesting.
它涵盖的话题真的很有趣。
Animal rights.
动物权利。
Do you really believe in that?
你真的相信那个吗？
If they're going to focus on something, they should do it on civil rights.
如果他们要把重点放在某件事上，应该放在民权上。
Yes, but we can't deny that animals are vulnerable, defenseless, and are completely at the mercy
是的，但我们不能否认动物是脆弱的、无助的，完全受制于
of human beings.
人类。
I understand your point, but we continue to have transgressions against human rights.
我理解你的观点，但我们仍然有侵犯人权的行为。
If so much attention weren't devoted to the topic of animals, we would then concentrate
如果对动物话题的关注不那么集中，我们就会更专注于拯救人类，
more on saving a human being instead of protecting a koala.
而不是保护一只考拉。
You can't compare apples and oranges.
你不能把苹果和橘子相提并论。
I believe that both topics are important and that we can't ignore them.
我相信这两个话题都很重要，我们不能忽视它们。
The mistreatment of animals can cause a great environmental imbalance.
虐待动物会导致严重的环境失衡。
I believe that governments should prohibit activities like poaching.
我认为政府应该禁止偷猎等活动。
Well, you are right on that point.
嗯，在那一点上你是对的。
This is the reason that I don't buy leather and I try to buy synthetic products.
这就是我不买皮革，并尽量买合成产品的原因。
At least you're doing your part.
至少你在尽自己的一份力。
My contribution is to have a pet in the house that I treat like a member of the family.
我的贡献是在家里养一只宠物，我把它当作家庭成员对待。
As long as you don't treat it better than your wife, it's fine.
只要你别对它比对你老婆还好，那就没问题。
All right, so a debatable topic, animals and animal rights.
好了，一个值得辩论的话题，动物和动物权利。
What do you think?
你怎么看？
Well, I'll say this.
嗯，我要说这个。
I would be a hypocrite if I said that it's bad to hurt animals because I'm a meat eater.
如果我说伤害动物不好，那我就是个伪君子，因为我吃肉。
I like to eat meat and I like to wear leather.
我喜欢吃肉，也喜欢穿皮革。
But I do think it's bad to mistreat animals.
但我确实认为虐待动物不好。
So I try to buy free-range chicken or meat from places I know that treat the animals
所以我尽量买散养鸡或来自我知道善待动物的地方的肉，
well and I definitely disagree with poaching and with using animals, especially endangered
而且我坚决反对偷猎和利用动物，尤其是濒危动物
animals for money and cash purposes.
来赚钱。
And so that's my position.
这就是我的立场。
But what's yours?
但你的立场呢？
I mean, I know you eat meat too.
我的意思是，我知道你也吃肉。
No, yeah, of course.
不，是的，当然。
And I think even though protection of animals is a very important topic and you don't want
而且我认为，尽管保护动物是一个非常重要的话题，你不想
the mistreatment of these little creatures that are very vulnerable to us because we're
虐待这些对我们来说非常脆弱的小生物，因为我们
smarter than them in the end.
最终比它们聪明。
But I think also it has to do a lot with superstition sometimes and kind of mystical and magical
但我也认为这有时与迷信以及某种神秘和神奇
things.
的事情有很大关系。
For example, people killing rhinos because they believe that the rhino horn has amazing
例如，人们杀死犀牛，因为他们相信犀牛角有神奇的
curing properties or the same thing with elephant tusks and stuff like that.
疗效，或者象牙之类的东西也一样。
So it also involves this certain aspect that people almost don't know any better.
所以这也涉及到一个方面，即人们几乎不知道更好的做法。
They just truly believe that these things actually work or that they will help them.
他们只是真心相信这些东西真的有效，或者会帮助他们。
So they don't consider the, like in the dialogue said, the imbalance that they create in the
所以他们不考虑，就像对话中说的，他们在环境中造成的
environment or the consequences.
失衡或后果。
Or there might be some very serious evolutionary consequences that we cannot even imagine.
或者可能会有一些我们甚至无法想象的非常严重的进化后果。
And so, you know, things change kind of over time, sometimes quickly and sometimes slowly.
所以，你知道，事情会随着时间的推移而变化，有时快，有时慢。
But if we force change really quickly, who knows what the results are going to be.
但如果我们强行快速改变，谁知道结果会是什么。
It might be really negative for us.
可能对我们非常不利。
Exactly.
没错。
And that's what we want to know now.
这就是我们现在想知道的。
What do you think about these topics?
你对这些话题怎么看？
Because in the end, the environment, animals, they're all connected.
因为最终，环境、动物，它们都是相互关联的。
If you wipe out all the foxes in a forest, then you're going to have too many snakes
如果你消灭了森林里所有的狐狸，那么你就会有太多蛇
running around, right?
到处乱跑，对吧？
So what do you think?
所以你怎么看？
Come to EnglishPod.com where you can leave all your questions, comments or suggestions.
来EnglishPod.com，你可以在那里留下所有问题、评论或建议。
And we're always there to help out.
我们随时都在那里帮忙。
So we hope to see you there.
所以我们希望在那里见到你。
And until next time, everyone, goodbye.
下次再见，各位，再见。
Bye.
再见。